Sofia Etchegoin - Full-Stack Developer

sofiaetchegoin@gmail.com | 02102326606 | github.com/sofia-etchegoin | linkedin.com/in/sofia-etchegoin-094417220 |

New Zealand Citizen

Kia ora! I am a full-stack developer with five years of public-sector experience in Wellington and one year of English teaching experience in Madrid. I transitioned into tech because it aligns with my skills and interest in project coordination, collaborative problem-solving, and continual learning. In pursuit of a challenge, I started teaching myself how to code last year and haven't looked back. Completing the bootcamp at Dev Academy Aotearoa further ignited a love for working with others to create well-designed applications. I am currently working on building a portfolio and a website for The Cheese Wheel; a Wellington-based cheese delivery business. I thrive in environments that are inclusive, supportive, and encourage knowledge-sharing. Building great software to help others excites me, and I'm looking forward to learning more.

EXPERIENCE

August - December 2023 | Dev Academy Aotearoa | Wellington

15-week bootcamp (total of 800 hours), working on software development projects in teams. My team's final project, 'Missing Purrson', is a website that lets users post details of their missing cats and sighting information to identify their pet's location. This project involved applying the full-stack we learnt and using the Google Maps APIs. I was the Team Lead, which involved facilitating meetings, leading the planning sessions, managing the team's workload and making key decisions about developing a high-quality product on time. You can view the final project showcase here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x1VW2teDogw&t=580s&ab_channel=DevAcademyAotearoa

October 2022 - July 2023 | English Language Assistant, Palas Atenea Institute | Madrid

Taught English lessons to classes of up to 30 high school students with a wide range of abilities. Showed leadership and communication skills, taking responsibility for being in charge of children.

April - October 2022 | Career break

October 2020 - April 2022 | Funds Advisor, Department of Conservation | Wellington

Negotiated and administered grants for conservation projects. Advised program directors on designing and delivering efficient funding processes.

June 2018 - September 2020 | Investment Coordinator, Ministry of Business, Innovation & Employment | Wellington

Lead the operations component of the Endeavour Fund; New Zealand's largest contestable fund. Coordinated end-to-end funding processes for administering grants to science research institutions.

October 2017 - May 2018 | Property Analyst, Ministry of Social Development | Wellington

Collaboratively developed business processes to manage government property portfolios.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript | React.js | REST APIs | HTML | CSS | Git | SQLite | Typescript | Node | Express | Jest

HUMAN SKILLS

Fast Learner | Teamwork and Leadership | Written & Verbal Communication | Self-Awareness

EDUCATION

- 2023 Dev Academy Aotearoa Applied Software Development, Level 6 Certificate
- 2022 Teaching English as a Foreign Language Certificate
- 2016 Chinese Proficiency Test (HSK) Level 4 Zhejiang University, China
- 2015 Bachelor of Science in Statistics & Chinese Victoria University of Wellington

ACCOLADES

2015 Prime Minister's Scholarship & Confucius Institute Scholarship

2014 Dean's List

2013 University Full Scholarship

LANGUAGES

English | Spanish | Mandarin

INTERESTS

Road Cycling and Mountain Biking | Swimming | Tramping | Reading

REFERENCES

Available on request